Amlan Banaji

Curriculum Vitae

Website: <u>amlan-</u> <u>banaji.github.io</u>

Email: A.F.Banaji "at" lboro.ac.uk

Nationality: UK

Research Associate in Fractal Geometry at Loughborough University's mathematics department since March 2023.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My main research interests relate to the geometry and dimension theory of fractal sets and measures. I have worked with fractals generated by conformal and non-conformal iterated function systems. I am currently interested in Fourier decay of fractal measures, and interpolating between different notions of dimension. I am interested in finding connections between fractal geometry and other areas of mathematics.

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

- 1. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. *Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors* **Transactions of the American Mathematical Society** 376 (2023), 2449–2479. <u>arXiv</u>
- 2. A. Banaji and A. Rutar. *Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions* **Annales Fennici Mathematici** 47 (2022), 939–960. <u>arXiv</u>
- 3. A. Banaji. *Metric spaces where geodesics are never unique* To appear in the **American Mathematical Monthly.** <u>arXiv</u>
- 4. A. Banaji and H. Chen. *Dimensions of popcorn-like pyramid sets* To appear in the **Journal of Fractal Geometry**. <u>arXiv</u>
- 5. A. Banaji and I. Kolossváry. *Intermediate dimensions of Bedford–McMullen carpets with applications to Lipschitz equivalence*Submitted. <u>arXiv</u>
- 6. A. Banaji. *Generalised intermediate dimensions* Submitted. <u>arXiv</u>
- 7. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. *Assouad type dimensions of infinitely generated self-conformal sets* Submitted, arXiv

EDUCATION

University of St Andrews

2019–present

PhD Mathematics

Topic: Fractal geometry and dimension theory

With the **Analysis Research Group**

Supervisors: Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Fully funded by the Leverhulme Trust

University of St Andrews

2018–2019

MSc Mathematics, Distinction

GPA: 19.5/20. Ranked 1st in the Faculty of Science and Medicine

Dissertation:

<u>Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains</u> (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by <u>Professor Kenneth Falconer</u>)

University of Cambridge,

King's College 2015–2018

BA (Hons) Mathematics

Selected Part II courses: Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

Thomas Tallis Sixth Form

2013–2015

A-Levels:

 $Mathematics(A^*)$, $Further\ Mathematics(A^*)$, $Physics(A^*)$, $Chemistry(A^*)$, History(A), $Extended\ Project\ Qualification(A^*,\ equivalent\ to\ half\ an\ A\ level)$

SELECTED PRIZES

2019: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best MSc student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

TALKS

I have given 23 talks (listed at amlan-banaji.github.io/talks) at conferences and seminar series including:

- One World Fractals (online, 18/1/23)
- Mathematics Research Day (St Andrews, 1/12/22)
- Szenzhen Technology University Mathematics Colloquium, (China (online), inaugural talk, 22/10/22)
- Fractals and Related Fields IV (Porquerolles, France, 5/9/22)
- Geometry of Deterministic and Random Fractals (Budapest University of Technology and Economics, 30/6/22)
- <u>Junior Ergodic Theory Meeting</u> (ICMS, Edinburgh (30/3/22) and online (19/3/21))
- Workshop on affine and overlapping iterated function systems (Bristol, 11/5/22)
- Dynamics and Group Geometry Early Researchers Seminar (DAGGER) (Warwick, 30/5/22 and 1/3/21)
- Analysis Seminar (St Andrews, 3/5/22, 12/10/21, 20/4/21, 30/6/20)

EXPERIENCE

Teaching undergraduate tutorials at the University of St Andrews:

Most recent student feedback score: 1.5 on a scale from 1 to 5 (where 1 is highest).

2019–2022: MT2502 Analysis (10 groups total)

2021: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- *2018–present:* **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with G5 Education, Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded **Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project** on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.
- 2017: internship at market research company Kantar TNS, working as a **data scientist** for the social media team, using Python.

SERVICE

- 2022: **Referee** for *Proc. Roy. Soc. Edinburgh Sect. A* and *J. Math. Anal. Appl.*
- 2022: **Organiser** of St Andrews Analysis Reading Group
- *2021*: **Co-organiser** of the Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews.
- 2019–2021: **Treasurer** of St Andrews Mindfulness Society.

MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES

- 2022–present: London Mathematical Society
- 2020–present: Edinburgh Mathematical Society
- 2019–present: Institute of Mathematics and its Applications

INTERESTS AND SKILLS

- **Languages:** English (native), German (conversational, A* at GCSE), Hindi (conversational)
- Music: Piano (grade 8), Clarinet (toured Canada and Venice)
- **Sport:** running, badminton, chess